# **Sunil Sharma**

(585) 483-4285 | Rochester, NY | ss4210@rit.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/sunil-sharma1991

## **Summary**

Enthusiastic and innovative graduate student at Rochester Institute of Technology, with a distinguished track record of **3 years** as **Product Manager** transitioned from the role of Software Engineer for **5 years** at global MNCs and unicorn startups.

#### Education

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

Master of Science, Product Development

Birla Institute of Technology and Sciences, Pilani, India

Master of Science, Software Engineering

March, 2017

Expected: December, 2022

### **Technical Skills**

**Functional** SDLC, Agile development, Requirement Gathering, Market Research, Stakeholder Management. Wireframing,

Product Roadmap, Technical Arch, SDLC, E-commerce, Product Launch, Product Management, SAAS, User

Stories, UI design, Data Analytics, Customer Engagement & Acquisition

**Technologies** Amazon Web Services, OpenShift, Apache Kafka, Hadoop, Elastic Search, SSIS, Magento, Docker, Kubernetes

**Analysis** A/B Testing and Experimentation, User Research, Usability Testing, Content Analysis, Clickstream, Data

Analysis, Data Modeling, Prediction using Classification and Regression using NLP and ML

Tools Kibana, Grafana, Google Analytics, Jenkins, JIRA, Github, Tableau, Draw.io, Figma, Microsoft Excel

**Certifications** Scrum Master Certification, Scrum Alliance, 2019 and Agile Practitioner

## **Professional Experience**

### Product Manager | Eyewa | Dubai, UAE

July 2020 - January 2021

- Led a team of product managers and associate product managers in designing and requirement gathering from stakeholders for the omni channel e-commerce platform for eyewear and lens in UAE with a traffic of 15000 daily active users
- Identified discrepancies in customer data using Google Analytics and MixPanel and led the designing of an in-house DataLake
- Collaborated with the design team, to optimize the B2C conversion funnel thus enabling users to perform 'checkout' operation faster resulting in increased yearly revenue by \$1.8M
- Performed cohort analysis in discovery funnel for incoming traffic on web and mobile app that identified an opportunity to reduce login and designed cart journey for powered eyeglasses resulting in boost yearly revenue by \$550,000
- Analyzed Delivery team activities to track, identify, and create shortest delivery routes across UAE from different warehouse locations
- Worked closely with sales and marketing in studying market trends and user feedback, and extrapolated data using MS Excel to clearly highlight to management and stakeholders the reports create from Hadoop Data Lake

## Product Lead | Barakat Group of Companies | Dubai, UAE

July 2019 – June 2020

- Developed and designed the architecture of an e-commerce platform in B2B and B2C environment from conceptualization to live stage
- · Communicated and collaborated with engineering, sales and marketing teams considering scope, requirements and budget
- Managed cross-functional teams and stakeholder communications and spearheaded the product development team scrum
- Designed and implemented A/B experiments for B2C website to improve the 'checkout' conversion funnel drop-ins, resulting a reduce in churn rate by 10 percent and improved 'add-to-cart' funnel by 16 % in following quarter
- Designed a Machine Language recommendation system for product pricing which improved Customer Lifetime Value by 32% annually
- Planned and implemented a referral program for active customers, which led to a net increase in new users of 72000 quarterly
- Collaborated with the Operation team in improving the 'Pick-and-Pack' process and reducing manually overhead of 1.5 hrs per Operations employee for an average of 150 orders handling capacity with 30 items bucket size
- Implemented Google Analytics dashboard (later updated to MixPanel) to identify product features that correlated with customer attrition, leading to proactive interventions that reduced monthly churn by 4%

### Solution Consultant | Flipkart Private Limited | Bangalore, India

Nov 2017 - July 2019

- Automated brand regulations and operations teams processes by implementing real-time monitoring for stages involving onboarding of new seller, 'Lead-to-Sign' and attrition of existing sellers, 'Sign-to-Live'
- Conducted seller interviews regarding underperforming areas of the B2B growth funnel and analyzed the usability issues of the seller platform
- Implemented a single click activation workflow for the sellers that led to a 12% increase in free trial activations for sellers' ads segment
- Worked directly with Product Owners and stakeholders on new product releases with backward compatibility and improved performances
- Implemented predictive recommendation ML model, in B2C mobile applications for categories based on User History and market trends which increased 35% CTR on website and mobile app storefront banners and sub-categories
- Build data visualization using SQL and Adobe Analytics data for product KPIs that reduced manual reporting work by 8 hours weekly
- · Participated in stakeholder meetings with a cross-functional team, and helped define go-to-market strategies
- Collaborated with the product manager to determine drop in seller platform subscribers, and modeled potential solutions in SQL, effectively increasing subscribers retention by 8 percent.

#### Senior Software Engineer | Wipro Technologies | Bangalore, India

January, 2015 - Nov 2017

- Designed and implemented an end-to-end IT Operation Analysis (ITOA) tool by integrating Zookeeper, Apache Kafka for data streaming, Apache Sparks for performing analysis and Hadoop
- Designed the architecture of the ITOA tool, performed technical analysis of each components and managed the development team till live
- Developed a tool to perform Sentiment Analysis of support ticket data using summary of its resolution with R language to understand the effectiveness of the support team and integrated this tool to ITOA platform
- · Performed data analysis on support data based on the different Key Performance Indexes using Natural language Processing algorithms
- Built a dashboard as a part of Center of Excellence-Project for Enterprise Release Management Organization team using Python
- Implemented services like MongoDB, SQL to compute efficient queries to fetch data and performed data analysis

### Software Engineer | Wipro Technologies | Bangalore, India

October 2012 - January 2015

- Supported Pitney Bowers, as a client for the Download Anywhere application team on the customer platform
- Developed a stand alone application that converted binary files to jpeg and integrated it with the reporting application to for exporting exports
- Developing features using the meter connection logs, analyzed downloaded images and registrations report and various other functionality that helps the end users to navigate through different segments of the online platform

### **Achievements**

- Awarded with merit-based scholarship from Kate Gleason College of Engineering, Rochester Institute of Technology
- Winner of **Best Hack-Marketplace Hackathon**, **2018** organized by Flipkart for developing a prototyped tool for personalized ads offers building based customer search history, buying affinity, previous payment structure and many more data points to give extensive approach in showcasing relevant and crips information to customer app or web platform
- · Honored with Eminent -Best Prodigy, 2017 from Manufacturing & Technology unit at Wipro Technologies
- · Awarded with Best New Incomer of the year, 2013 in Networking unit at Wipro Technologies for CapitalOne